Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we're going to continue in our series about job interviews.
我是Catherine，今天我们将继续关于求职面试的系列节目。
That's right.
没错。
And on this occasion we're taking a look at part five of our interview series where we
这次我们来看面试系列的第五部分，内容是关于
explain why we left our previous job.
解释我们为什么离开上一份工作。
Okay, and so in an interview, this is a very popular question.
好的，在面试中，这是一个非常常见的问题。
Why did you leave your last job?
你为什么离开上一份工作？
Learn some tools for answering this question in today's dialogue.
在今天的对话中，学习一些回答这个问题的技巧。
We're going to take a listen to it first and we'll be back in a moment.
我们先听一遍对话，稍后再回来。
Okay, now I'd like to find out more about your last job.
好的，现在我想多了解一些你上一份工作的情况。
I see you spent almost four years at the London Weekly.
我看到你在《伦敦周刊》工作了将近四年。
Is that right?
是这样吗？
Yes, that's right.
是的，没错。
To be honest, the first year was quite tough for me.
说实话，第一年对我来说相当艰难。
I was really just treated more like an intern.
我基本上被当作实习生对待。
I didn't have many responsibilities and I found it quite frustrating.
我没有太多责任，这让我感到很沮丧。
So, what changed?
那么，后来发生了什么变化？
Well, slowly but surely I proved myself and the new editor liked me so he promoted me
嗯，慢慢地我证明了自己，新主编很喜欢我，所以他提拔我
to Features Writer.
成为专题撰稿人。
Wow, a real step up.
哇，真是升职了。
Yes, I was responsible for restaurant and food reviews mostly.
是的，我主要负责餐厅和美食评论。
I spent three years in that position.
我在那个职位上干了三年。
But to be honest, it wasn't an area of journalism I wanted to stay in long term.
但说实话，那并不是我想长期从事的新闻领域。
I see.
我明白了。
So why did you decide to leave finally?
那你最后为什么决定离开呢？
I just felt that the paper couldn't offer me any new opportunities.
我只是觉得这家报纸无法给我提供新的机会。
I really needed a more challenging role to be honest.
说实话，我真的需要一个更有挑战性的角色。
Alright, we're back and as we saw, Rebecca handled it quite well explaining why you left
好了，我们回来了，正如我们看到的，Rebecca处理得很好，她解释了为什么离开
your last job because obviously you don't want to say something like, I just really
上一份工作，因为显然你不想说类似“我就是真的
didn't like my company or the boss was a really bad guy.
不喜欢我的公司”或“老板是个坏人”这样的话。
Or I was fired for being lazy.
或者“我因为懒惰被解雇了”。
Exactly.
没错。
So, why don't we take a look at a couple of different words on Language Takeaway.
那么，我们来看看“语言小贴士”中的几个不同词汇吧。
Language Takeaway.
语言小贴士。
Okay, so we've got some great descriptive words here.
好的，这里有一些很棒的描述性词汇。
These are some adjectives.
这些是一些形容词。
The first one is tough.
第一个是“tough”。
So Rebecca said, to be honest, the first year was quite tough for me.
所以Rebecca说：“说实话，第一年对我来说相当艰难。”
Alright, so she's describing that her first year at that company where she was working,
好的，她在描述她在那家公司工作的第一年
it was tough and that means hard, difficult.
很“tough”，意思是困难、艰难。
That's right.
没错。
You could say, this is a really tough situation.
你可以说：“这是一个非常棘手的情况。”
That means it's a difficult situation.
意思是这是一个困难的情况。
It's hard because there's no easy answer.
很难，因为没有简单的答案。
Exactly.
没错。
So, if you describe something as tough, it means that it's very difficult.
所以，如果你描述某事为“tough”，意思是它非常困难。
Now there is another meaning to this where it can be that you are a strong person.
这个词还有另一个意思，可以指你是一个坚强的人。
Right.
对。
So that's different because we're talking about a person, not a situation.
这不一样，因为我们说的是人，而不是情况。
But if you're talking about a job or an experience or even homework, like this homework is really
但如果你在谈论一份工作、一段经历甚至作业，比如“这个作业真
tough, it means that it's very hard.
难”，意思是它非常困难。
Exactly.
没错。
So apart from her job being a little bit tough, she said that it was also a little bit frustrating.
所以除了她的工作有点艰难之外，她还说这也有点令人沮丧。
Okay, so usually these things go together.
好的，通常这些事情是相伴而生的。
If something is tough, like it's difficult, it's usually frustrating too.
如果某事很艰难，比如很困难，通常也会令人沮丧。
So in this case, something is frustrating when it makes you unhappy or for example,
所以在这种情况下，当某事让你不开心，或者例如
it makes you feel stressed.
让你感到压力时，它就是令人沮丧的。
So something that's frustrating is not a good thing.
所以令人沮丧的事情不是好事。
Exactly.
没错。
So as you gave the example with the homework assignment, if you have maybe a math assignment
就像你举的作业例子，如果你有一道数学题
that's very difficult and you can't solve it, you don't find the solution, then you
非常难，你解不出来，找不到答案，那么你
get frustrated.
就会感到沮丧。
You get maybe angry at yourself or you get very angry for not being able to solve it.
你可能会生自己的气，或者因为解不出来而非常生气。
So that's when something is frustrating.
这就是令人沮丧的情况。
I hate being frustrated.
我讨厌感到沮丧。
Exactly.
没错。
Well, it's not a nice feeling.
嗯，这不是一种好感觉。
But she said that, well, it was frustrating, it was tough, but after a while, I proved
但她说，嗯，虽然令人沮丧、很艰难，但过了一段时间，我证明
myself.
了自己。
Okay, so that means that she was able to show someone that she can handle difficult things,
好的，这意味着她能够向某人展示她能处理困难的事情、
difficult work, difficult situations.
困难的工作、困难的情况。
And so she said, I proved myself and the new editor liked me.
所以她说：“我证明了自己，新主编很喜欢我。”
So basically, she did a really good job.
所以基本上，她做得很好。
Exactly.
没错。
So if you prove yourself, you're showing someone that you have great ability or capabilities
所以如果你“prove yourself”，你是在向某人展示你有很强的能力或才干，
of solving a problem or being able to handle a difficult job.
能解决问题或胜任困难的工作。
That's right.
没错。
So you could say, last year, Bob didn't do very well at school, but this year, he really
所以你可以说：“去年Bob在学校表现不太好，但今年，他真的
proved himself.
证明了自己。”
He studied hard and he got really good grades.
他努力学习，取得了非常好的成绩。
Exactly.
没错。
And well, Rebecca, what she got in exchange for proving herself, she got promoted.
而丽贝卡，她通过证明自己换来了什么？她升职了。
This is great.
这太棒了。
So promotions are good things.
所以升职是好事。
The verb here is to promote or to be promoted.
这里的动词是“promote”或“be promoted”。
So in this case, she was promoted.
所以在这个例子中，她升职了。
You could say, last year, I was promoted or he will be promoted next week.
你可以说，去年我升职了，或者他下周会升职。
He doesn't know yet.
他还不知道。
Exactly.
没错。
Now, remember that to be promoted means to get a better position in your job.
记住，“be promoted”意味着在工作中获得更好的职位。
Now, as we mentioned, the verb is to promote and you may be asking yourself why we are
现在，正如我们提到的，动词是“promote”，你可能会问为什么我们
using the verb to be in the past, was promoted.
使用过去式的“to be”动词“was promoted”。
And this is because it's an ed adjective.
这是因为它是一个以“ed”结尾的形容词。
It's an adjective that ends in ed.
它是一个以“ed”结尾的形容词。
So you may think it's a verb, but it's not.
所以你可能会认为它是动词，但其实不是。
It's actually an adjective.
它实际上是一个形容词。
The verb here is to be.
这里的动词是“to be”。
Exactly.
没错。
So I was promoted.
所以“I was promoted”。
So was is obviously our verb here, the verb to be, but promoted is an adjective that ends
所以“was”显然是我们这里的动词，即“to be”，但“promoted”是一个以“ed”结尾的形容词。
in ed.
Okay.
好的。
And so if I'm the boss, the action I do, the verb I do is I promote someone.
所以如果我是老板，我做的动作，我用的动词是“I promote someone”。
So this can be a little bit tricky, but we recommend that you check out the website for
这可能会有点棘手，但我们建议你去网站查看
more details because we have lots of examples of how to use this.
更多细节，因为我们有很多如何使用它的例子。
Exactly.
没错。
Well, she got promoted and well, she was really happy for a while, but then she said, you
嗯，她升职了，她开心了一段时间，但后来她说，你知道吗，我真的需要一个更有挑战性的角色，一份更有挑战性的工作。
know what, I really needed a more challenging role, a more challenging job.
Okay.
好的。
Challenging is a great adjective.
“Challenging”是一个很棒的形容词。
It means something is difficult or it gives you a challenge.
它意味着某事很难，或者给你一个挑战。
So that means it's not easy.
所以这意味着它不容易。
Yeah.
是的。
So she found that her job was a little bit too easy.
所以她发现她的工作有点太简单了。
So she wanted something a little bit more challenging.
所以她想要一些更有挑战性的东西。
Okay.
好的。
And so this is a really great word for job interviews in particular, because you're basically
这是一个在求职面试中特别好的词，因为你基本上
saying, I want hard work.
在说，我想要努力工作。
I want to prove myself.
我想证明自己。
There we go again.
又来了。
So I want to show you that I'm a good employee or a hard worker.
所以我想向你展示我是一个好员工或勤奋的人。
And so I want a challenge, something that's hard.
所以我想要一个挑战，一些困难的事情。
Exactly.
没错。
So something that is hard is a challenge or you want something challenging.
所以困难的事情是挑战，或者你想要有挑战性的东西。
So why don't we review these words that we've taken a look at now.
那么，我们为什么不回顾一下我们刚才看过的这些词呢？
Let's go back to the dialogue and listen to it again.
让我们回到对话，再听一遍。
Okay.
好的。
Now I'd like to find out more about your last job.
现在我想多了解你上一份工作。
I see you spent almost four years at the London Weekly.
我看到你在《伦敦周刊》待了将近四年。
Is that right?
对吗？
Yes, that's right.
是的，没错。
To be honest, the first year was quite tough for me.
说实话，第一年对我来说相当艰难。
I was really just treated more like an intern.
我真的只是被当作实习生对待。
I didn't have many responsibilities and I found it quite frustrating.
我没有太多责任，我觉得这很令人沮丧。
So what changed?
那是什么改变了呢？
Well slowly but surely I proved myself and the new editor liked me.
嗯，慢慢地但肯定地，我证明了自己，新编辑喜欢我。
So he promoted me to features writer.
所以他把我提升为专题作家。
Wow.
哇。
A real step up.
真是进步了一大步。
Yes.
是的。
I was responsible for restaurant and food reviews.
我负责餐厅和美食评论。
Mostly I spent three years in that position.
大部分时间我在那个职位上待了三年。
But to be honest, it wasn't an area of journalism I wanted to stay in long term.
但说实话，这不是我想长期从事的新闻领域。
I see.
我明白了。
So why did you decide to leave finally?
那你为什么最终决定离开呢？
I just felt that the paper couldn't offer me any new opportunities.
我只是觉得这家报纸不能给我提供任何新机会。
I really needed a more challenging role to be honest.
说实话，我真的需要一个更有挑战性的角色。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now let's take a look at a couple of phrases we picked out for you on Fluency Builder.
现在让我们看看我们在“流利度构建器”中为你挑选的几个短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
Okay, this first phrase is unusual because it actually happens at the end of sentences.
好的，第一个短语不寻常，因为它实际上出现在句子末尾。
This is very, very common with people who are making small talk or who are doing interviews.
这在闲聊或面试的人中非常非常常见。
This is the phrase, is that right?
这个短语是“is that right?”。
So basically you saw that in the first line Mr. Parsons was talking to her and said, well,
所以基本上你在第一行看到帕森斯先生和她说话，说，嗯，
I see you spent almost four years at the London Weekly.
我看到你在《伦敦周刊》待了将近四年。
Is that right?
对吗？
So he's ending the sentence with this phrase.
所以他用这个短语结束句子。
So he's making the sentence a question.
所以他让句子变成了疑问句。
I see that you did this.
我看到你做了这个。
Is that right?
是这样吗？
So he's asking her to confirm the fact that he knows about her because maybe they've never
所以他是在请她确认他知道她这件事，因为也许他们之前从未
really talked before.
真正交谈过。
So this is a good way for him to ask her to give more details.
所以这是他请她提供更多细节的好方法。
So for example, Marco, I hear that you're from Ecuador.
比如，Marco，我听说你来自厄瓜多尔。
Is that right?
是这样吗？
That's right.
没错。
So apart from ending the sentence like this, if maybe somebody asks you, is that right?
所以除了像这样结束句子，如果有人问你，是这样吗？
You have to confirm.
你必须确认。
You have to say, yes, that's right.
你必须说，是的，没错。
Or yes.
或者是的。
It's also good to elaborate, to give more details.
最好再详细说明，提供更多细节。
So yes, I'm from Ecuador.
所以是的，我来自厄瓜多尔。
I was born there, but I've lived in the United States.
我出生在那里，但我住在美国。
This is a way to give more information because that's basically what the person's asking.
这是提供更多信息的方式，因为那基本上就是对方在问的。
Yeah, I think it wouldn't be very good if you're at a job interview and the person says,
是的，我觉得如果你在面试时，对方说，
is that right?
是这样吗？
And you say, yes, that's right.
然后你说，是的，没错。
And then you don't say anything else.
然后你就不说话了，那就不太好。
So yeah, basically the point is you have to confirm or deny.
所以是的，基本上要点是你必须确认或否认。
You have to say, yes, that's right or no, that's not right.
你必须说，是的，没错，或者不，不是这样。
And then you have to give some information about the question.
然后你必须就问题提供一些信息。
Exactly.
没错。
All right.
好的。
Now, moving on, when Rebecca again was talking about her job, she was saying it's tough and
现在，继续，当Rebecca再次谈到她的工作时，她说工作很艰难，
I didn't have many responsibilities and I found it quite frustrating.
我没有太多责任，我觉得很沮丧。
Okay.
好的。
So this is like lost and found.
这就像失物招领。
Like I lost my hat and I found it later.
比如我丢了帽子，后来找到了。
No, no.
不，不。
This is what's interesting about this verb, find.
这就是这个动词“find”有趣的地方。
We are not actually looking for something or we didn't actually find something we were
我们并不是真的在找东西，或者我们并没有真的找到我们正在找的东西。
looking for.
找的东西。
This is kind of a realization, right?
这更像是一种领悟，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
It's like a feeling.
这像是一种感觉。
So I find this movie boring.
所以我觉得这部电影很无聊。
That means I think this movie is boring.
意思是说我认为这部电影很无聊。
It's the way that you're thinking about something.
这是你对某事的看法。
That's right.
没错。
Or you can say, oh, I found Paris to be quite an expensive city.
或者你可以说，哦，我觉得巴黎是个相当昂贵的城市。
Yeah, pretty expensive.
是的，相当贵。
So this is your impression.
所以这是你的印象。
This is the way that you feel about something.
这是你对某事的感受。
Exactly.
没错。
So this is another way that you can use this word to find.
所以这是使用“find”这个词的另一种方式。
Now again, when Rebecca talked about proving herself, she used a very interesting, I would
现在，当Rebecca谈到证明自己时，她用了一个非常有趣的，我会说
say phrase, a very popular well-known phrase, slowly but surely.
短语，一个非常流行的著名短语，“slowly but surely”。
Okay.
好的。
So slowly but surely is the opposite of right away.
所以“slowly but surely”是“right away”的反义词。
Right?
对吧？
So something that happens right away is immediate.
所以立即发生的事情是即时的。
Like I got promoted right away.
比如我立刻升职了。
But slowly but surely means after lots of time and even hard work, this good thing happened.
但“slowly but surely”意味着经过很长时间甚至努力工作后，这件好事发生了。
Or it's usually a good thing, actually.
或者通常是一件好事，实际上。
Yeah.
是的。
You're basically saying that you didn't do anything very quickly, but you did it very
你基本上是说，你没有很快做任何事，但你做得非常
well.
好。
So slowly but surely, I finished building my home.
所以“slowly but surely”，我建好了我的房子。
Right.
对。
So it didn't happen overnight, but it did happen over time.
所以它不是一夜之间发生的，但它是随着时间的推移发生的。
You can also say this about studying a language.
你也可以这样说学习语言。
At the beginning, learning English was really hard, but slowly but surely, I became fluent.
一开始，学英语真的很难，但“slowly but surely”，我变得流利了。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So slowly but surely.
所以“slowly but surely”。
And the last phrase that we have for you today, you may have seen that Rebecca used this phrase,
今天我们为你准备的最后一个短语，你可能看到Rebecca在解释某事之前用了这个短语，
to be honest, a couple of times before explaining something.
“to be honest”，好几次。
So why does she say to be honest?
所以她为什么说“to be honest”？
To be honest is sometimes something we say in English to fill some space or some time.
“To be honest”有时是我们在英语中用来填补空间或时间的话。
We call it filler.
我们称之为填充词。
But it's also a way to introduce something that's negative.
但它也是引入负面内容的一种方式。
So for example, in this dialogue, she's talking about her negative experiences.
比如，在这个对话中，她在谈论她的负面经历。
My job was tough.
我的工作很艰难。
My experience was bad.
我的经历很糟糕。
So she says, to be honest, it wasn't the best experience, but I learned from it.
所以她说，“to be honest”，这不是最好的经历，但我从中吸取了教训。
She's saying this to introduce some things that are maybe not positive, not happy things.
她说这个是为了引入一些可能不是积极、不是愉快的事情。
That's right.
没错。
So it's another way of saying, look, I'm going to tell you the truth.
所以这是另一种说法，听着，我要告诉你真相。
It may not be something positive, but this is what happened.
可能不是积极的事，但这就是发生的事情。
So to be honest, I didn't really like my last employer or something like that.
老实说，我其实不太喜欢我上一个雇主之类的。
Right.
没错。
We can even talk about this with your friends.
我们甚至可以用这个跟朋友聊天。
So hey, Marco, did you like that movie Shutter Island?
嘿，马可，你喜欢《禁闭岛》那部电影吗？
To be honest, I didn't really see it.
老实说，我其实没看过。
Oh.
哦。
I fell asleep.
我睡着了。
Or you could say, to be honest, I didn't love it.
或者你可以说，老实说，我不太喜欢它。
I didn't really like it.
我其实不太喜欢。
Exactly.
正是。
So it's a very good phrase, but don't overuse it.
所以这是个很好的短语，但别用得太频繁。
I think sometimes you get into the habit of using it all the time and just like, like,
我觉得有时候你会养成一直用它的习惯，就像，像，
you know, well, you know, like I went to the movies like yesterday, like, and like, to
你知道，嗯，比如我昨天去了电影院，比如，然后，比如，老实说，
be honest, like, so try to keep these fillers as you described them to a minimum.
所以尽量把你说的这些填充词减到最少。
So don't really use them too much.
所以别用太多。
Yes.
是的。
Say thoughts and ideas.
说出想法和观点。
Nice action verbs, not too much fillers, because sometimes, especially in an interview,
用好的动作动词，别用太多填充词，因为有时候，尤其是在面试中，
it makes people think that you don't really know much to say.
会让人觉得你其实没什么可说的。
Yeah, exactly.
对，没错。
Okay.
好的。
So listen to the dialogue for the last time and we'll be back to chat a little bit more.
那么，最后一次听这段对话，之后我们再回来聊一聊。
Okay.
好的。
Now I'd like to find out more about your last job.
现在我想多了解一下你上一份工作。
I see you spent almost four years at the London Weekly.
我看到你在《伦敦周刊》工作了将近四年。
Is that right?
是这样吗？
Yes, that's right.
是的，没错。
To be honest, the first year was quite tough for me.
说实话，第一年对我来说挺难的。
I was really just treated more like an intern.
我基本上被当作实习生对待。
I didn't have many responsibilities and I found it quite frustrating.
我没什么责任，这让我觉得很沮丧。
So what changed?
那后来发生了什么变化？
Well slowly but surely I proved myself and the new editor liked me so he promoted me
嗯，慢慢地我证明了自己，新来的编辑喜欢我，所以他提拔了我
to Features Writer.
成为专题撰稿人。
Wow, a real step up.
哇，真是升了一级。
Yes, I was responsible for restaurant and food reviews mostly.
是的，我主要负责餐厅和美食评论。
I spent three years in that position.
我在那个职位上干了三年。
But to be honest, it wasn't an area of journalism I wanted to stay in long term.
但说实话，那不是我长期想从事的新闻领域。
I see.
我明白了。
So why did you decide to leave finally?
那你最后为什么决定离开？
I just felt that the paper couldn't offer me any new opportunities.
我只是觉得这家报纸不能再给我提供新的机会了。
I really needed a more challenging role to be honest.
老实说，我确实需要一个更有挑战性的角色。
Alright so talking about your last employer, this is a pretty ideal thing.
好的，那么谈到你上一份工作，这是一个相当理想的话题。
Now do you have any advice that you can give our listeners about describing your last job?
现在，你能给我们的听众一些关于描述上一份工作的建议吗？
Why did you leave your previous employer?
你为什么离开上一份工作？
Well I do have a little bit of basic job advice.
嗯，我确实有一些基本的求职建议。
I would say don't complain about your last employer.
我会说，不要抱怨你上一份工作。
Don't say my boss was mean, my co-workers were lazy, my company was terrible because
不要说“我的老板很刻薄，我的同事很懒，我的公司很糟糕”，因为
usually as a person doing an interview, that makes you think that this person, if they
通常作为面试官，这会让你觉得，如果这个人
work for you, will complain about you.
为你工作，他也会抱怨你。
And so I think it's important like what Rebecca does in this dialogue to keep it positive.
所以我认为像丽贝卡在这段对话中那样保持积极态度很重要。
Every negative situation can become a positive experience.
每个负面情况都可以变成一次积极的经历。
So the job was tough but it was a good challenge, right?
所以工作很艰难，但这是一个很好的挑战，对吧？
Or but she learned how to do many new things.
或者她学会了如何做很多新事情。
I think this is important for anybody in any language but in English especially to use
我认为这对任何语言的人来说都很重要，但在英语中尤其要使用
some of these phrases and to say, you know, I really like a challenge or I didn't feel
这些短语，比如说，“我真的很喜欢挑战”或“我觉得
this was challenging enough, things like this.
这不够有挑战性”之类的话。
As opposed to, my old boss is so mean, he made me work on the weekends, that company
而不是说“我以前的老板太刻薄了，他让我周末工作，那家公司
is so terrible.
太糟糕了。”
I mean that kind of stuff no one wants to hear.
我的意思是，那种话没人想听。
Yeah exactly and I think it's not really useful because even if the company is the competitor,
是的，没错，而且我认为这没什么用，因为即使那家公司是竞争对手，
so you don't really get any extra points for giving them like the dirty secrets of what
所以，你透露公司内部那些肮脏的秘密并不会给你加分。
was going on in the company.
公司里发生了什么。
Maybe saying, oh my co-workers, they were just so mean to me and stuff like this.
也许你会说，哦，我的同事对我太刻薄了之类的话。
Yeah, no, it makes you seem like a complainer and no one wants to hire a complainer.
是啊，不，这只会让你看起来像个爱抱怨的人，没人愿意雇一个爱抱怨的人。
Exactly.
没错。
Alright so this is an interesting topic we would like to hear from you.
好了，这是个有趣的话题，我们想听听你的看法。
So come to EnglishPod.com and tell us why did you leave your previous employer?
所以，来EnglishPod.com告诉我们，你为什么离开上一份工作？
Or just let us know about some of your interview experiences or some of your interview questions.
或者，跟我们分享一些你的面试经历或面试问题。
We're happy to help you out.
我们很乐意帮助你。
We'll hope to see you at the website.
我们期待在网站上见到你。
Alright we'll see you there.
好了，我们那儿见。
Bye.
再见。
Shannon Jonesiffs3